Wie haben Sie Ihre ersten Jahre im Kibbuz Nahal Oz erlebt? Was hat Sie damals dazu bewegt, dort zu leben?
I came here when I was in my 20s,
I came to study.
There is a very good college,
it's the best in Israel,
about a 10-minute drive from here.
So many people
come to this area in order to become students.
So the reasons
I chose Nahal Oz were because
the rent was fair, they had plenty of young people here,
and they said I could bring my dog,
those were the elements taken into consideration.
My political views...
It had nothing to do with my political views,
I always was,
I was in my entire life left-leaning.
always voted
center-left, and apparently it was a fit,
because the people on the kibbutz,
on this kibbutz,
the numbers are quite astonishing,
92% of the people here used to vote center-left.
We still haven’t had a new election,
so I don’t know what will happen after October 7th,
but this is the left stronghold
of Israel, the Gaza envelope.
People here really believed in
working with the palestinians.
There was...
I'm just...
It will probably come up in the other questions.
So when I arrived here,
I arrived in 2002
and the rockets on Nahal Oz began a year before that.
But still it was very simple rockets,
it wasn't what we have today.
It was like a light-years difference.
Damage from a rocket hit
would be something the size
the size of a regular ashtray.
Something like this and this.
And I still didn’t have children,
which is a huge game changer,
so I came here and
I remember that we were sitting outside.
All the friends, and
in the evening and there was an alarm or something,
we wouldn’t even get up.
Back then.
But then things started escalating seriously after that.